<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Chinese | Brian Sunter]]></title>
  <link href="http://brsunter.github.io/blog/categories/chinese/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brsunter.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-15T13:28:50-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://brsunter.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Sunter]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Studying Abroad in China: Pre departure]]></title>
    <link href="http://brsunter.github.io/blog/2010/04/14/studying-abroad-in-china-pre-departure/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-14T22:43:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brsunter.github.io/blog/2010/04/14/studying-abroad-in-china-pre-departure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone!
As many of you know, I have the incredible opportunity to study abroad
this summer in China. I plan to use this blog to keep you all updated on
my adventures(and possibly misadventures) on the other side of the
world. I’m sure my parents will want to know I’m still alive and haven’t
overdosed on Sichuan peppercorns. I’ll try to give you guys all the
details on my trip, so be prepared for some ridiculous stories. The
Chinese government blocks many websites, including Facebook and Gmail,
so this blog and Skype will be my primary links to the western world.
Making telephone calls will be prohibitively expensive, so add me on
Skype if you’d like to talk. My username is brsunter.
<img src="/images/blog/china-map.jpg" alt="A Map of China, I'll be in the Sichuan Province" />
When I tell someone I’m studying abroad in China, the first they say is
“Whoa! I didn’t know you spoke Chinese.” and are even more surprised
when I tell them “Well actually, I don’t know how yet.” You heard me
right: I’m about to travel to china for 97 days and I can only speak a
tiny bit of Mandarin. The program I’m signed up for is called “UF in
Chengdu” and is intended for students with no prior experience who
couldn’t get into the Beginning Chinese classes during the fall. As you
can imagine, this is a little nerve wracking. China has such a radically
different culture than the US and I’ll barely be able to ask for
directions when I first get there. However, I’m making pretty good
progress with just my self study, so I’m confident that when I actually
get there, start taking classes, and “ni hao”-ing everyone in my path
I’ll improve quickly . I have some Chinese speaking friends at school
helping me out with my pronunciation. Pronouncing the word correctly is
extremely important in Mandarin, where the tone of your voice means the
difference between ” May I ask you…” and “May I kiss you?” I’ll be sure
to let all of you if my poor grasp of the Chinese language leads to any
romance.</p>

<p>So, why am I studying Chinese? Well, I’ve always thought China was a
fascinating place. I’ve always loved travelling and experiencing new
things and China is about as different as it gets. No matter how much I
read about it, I still feel like can’t understand it or get a clear
picture of what things are really like. China is poised to become even
more influential in the world and will definitely be a bigger player in
world politics in the future. I believe actually living somewhere and
learning the language are essential to completely understand a place and
I hope to have a much better grasp of Chinese culture by the time I get
back.I’ve been fortunate enough to travel to many places in my life, but
I’ve never actually spent an extended amount anywhere outside of
Florida. I’ve lived within 3 hours of where I was born for my entire
life. Living abroad is definitely going to be a very enriching
experience.</p>

<p>One thing in particular that I’m looking forward to is the wealth of
history there. The Chinese civilization has been around for about 5000
years and there is just so much history and historical sites like the
Forbidden City and the Great Wall. China is a huge country, so there’s
no way I’ll get so see everything, but hopefully I can make it to some
of the most popular sites. If any of you have been there and have
suggestions of places to visit, please send them my way!</p>

<p>This trip will be the longest I’ve ever travelled. I leave from Tampa on
May 5th and arrive in Chengdu on May 7th…two days later.  The total
travel time is about 36 hours including layovers. I loaded up my kindle
with a plethora of books and stocked up on Nintendo DS games so
hopefully I won’t be too bored. Thankfully I’m on the flight with some
other people in my group, which will make things much much easier. At
least if I wind up stranded in a Chinese airport, I won’t be all by
myself.</p>

<p>The city I’m studying in is called Chengdu(成都), in the Sichuan
Province. You may notice that the name “Sichuan” sounds similar to the
spicy “Szechuan” chicken dish you’ve probably ordered in Chinese
restaurants. Well, this is its origin and this particular province
happens to be one of the spicy food capitals of the world. This is a
dream come true for me because I love eating the spiciest foods I can
find. Apparently they have a pepper there that  makes your mouth go
completely numb. This is definitely on the top of my list of foods to
try. Chengdu is a relatively large city, but not quite as large as
Beijing or Shanghai. Even though its somewhat populous, its famed for
the relaxed and laid back attitude of the locals.</p>

<p>The city of Chengdu
The particular college I’ll be studying at is the Southwestern
University of Finance and Economics(SWUFE) and its located right in the
middle of the city. The campus and accommodations seem really nice, so
I’ll definitely be comfortable there.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/swufe-campus.jpeg" alt="A view of the SWUFE campus" />
<img src="/images/blog/swufe-field.jpg" alt="Soccer fields and the gym" />
The program I’m doing at UF is called “UF in Chengdu” which I’ll be
taking with 16 other UF students. Over the summer I’ll take Beginning
Chinese 1, Beginning Chinese 2, and a Chinese culture class. The culture
class seems really fun because it looks like we’ll be doing things like
cooking, calligraphy, and traditional art. The program has a couple of
excursions planned for us, such as trips to temples, mountains, and the
Giant Panda Breeding research center(where we’ll be able to hold baby
pandas!). Besides the planned excursions, I definitely plan to travel
around a lot myself. We have a 1 week break in the middle of the
program, so I would like to see more the country, especially the east
coast. I’ve been told there is some excellent hiking and scenery around
Chengdu, so hopefully some of the other members of my group will join
me. I can’t say I know the other students all that well yet, but if
they’re adventurous enough to study abroad in China with no experience
then I’m sure they’re my kind of people. I will return to the US on
August, 11th. That’s all for now! Click the link below this post to
leave a commenta</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
